<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[George Samartzopoulos | architecture & urbanism]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[George Samartzopoulos | architecture & urbanism]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 21:34:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[City Home]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>City Home</h1><p>The cost to live in an urban area is increasingly out of reach
for young professionals. With scarcity of space, cost to rent
or buy is escalating whilst the standard of living is
compromised. The transformable city-home takes
advantage of a clever arrangement of simple mechanical
systems to allow for many different uses of a single space –
fit for young professionals with similarly flexible lifestyles. In
doing so, the overall living space can be compacted into a
simple 15 x 15 feet micro unit, allowing the space to be
s imul ta neous l y luxur ious a nd a f fordabl e . The
transformability comes in the form of a thickened ceiling
from which different surfaces can descend, transforming the
small unit from one activity to another without taking any
floor space. The City Home takes advantage of the fact that
many activities can be available on demand, instead of
taking up space in the home at all times. Only the kitchen
and bathroom are relatively fixed and available at any given
moment. This creates a flexible building system where
different 'activities' can be installed into the ceiling based
upon the needs and preferences of each tenant, while the
building structure and chassis never needs to change. The
drop ceiling of the room maximizes the space efficiency of
the room and makes it possible to have the highest flexibility.
The largest pieces of furniture – the bed and the worktable
can be elevated and hidden above the drop ceiling during
day time to make the room space clear for other activities.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4dbc7f4b964a5d4d2cf7afab6ee24a2fa3f84f54.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/75a8994a-b706-47e4-901d-f4f96c989db9/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">75a8994a-b706-47e4-901d-f4f96c989db9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 21:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MIXED USE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE & CULTURAL SPACES]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>MIXED USE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE & CULTURAL SPACES</h1><p>Design of a buildings complex which accommodates
multiple different uses. It includes exhibition spaces, a
conference hall, office and seminar spaces, a library and a
restaurant. The main organizational elements of the design
are the atriums, which connect floors that have different
uses. The office spaces and the restaurant are placed on the
front part of the plot in order to have the view of the adjacent
park. The exhibition spaces are organized in an open plan
configuration and are placed away from the adjacent noisy
highway. They are connected with a continuous ramp which
begins at the ground floor and runs through multiple floors.
Great emphasis is given to the integration of the overall
complex in the adjacent urban web. The buildings organize
the pedestrian movements on the ground level, thus,
becoming a passage and an active part of the urban web.
The rotation of the grid in the plan gives the impression of a
formal break and the penetration of one form through
another. The two main uses of the building are expressed
with different construction systems. The metallic structure
accommodates office and seminar spaces. The concrete
structure includes the exhibition spaces and the restaurant.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/21ec20a3dda4bdafd637ac30f147bfe2fb548f79.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/mixed-use-development-office-and-cultural-spaces/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">85f56471-2f79-486e-a6bb-198175505776</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:31:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LIANTANG - HEUNG YUEN WAI 03 BOUNDARY CONTROL POINT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>LIANTANG - HEUNG YUEN WAI 03 BOUNDARY CONTROL POINT</h1><p>Masterplan for the boundary control point between the
Shenzhen territory, China and Hong Kong. The proposal aims
to reform the existing landscape and design an independent
island which accommodates logistics and market spaces
and an extensive vehicular mobility infrastructure. All these
spaces are placed under the large scale roof. They are
organized on different levels and have direct access to the
wild ecosystem that lies above them. The exterior surface of
the structure aims to extend the existing landscape which is
subject to destruction due to the extensive pollution in the
area. The proposal suggests the creation of four different
zones of landscape which respond to the existing flora in the
territory. The interior space includes technological equipment
for the production of energy and the absorption of air
pollution. The infrastructure becomes energy efficient by
using piezoelectric systems, solar panels and taking
advantage of the changes of the temperature of the river. As
an example, the piezoelectric technology system produces
1.5MW from the average 30.000 vehicles that pass through
the territory everyday. The air pollutants from the vehicles are
absorbed from the exterior surface which includes specific
types of flora and bacteria. Finally, the proposal aims to
redefine the boundary conditions between the two countries
with the design of an independent island which improves the
mobility of people and the exchange of goods.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/e2de9786a04e8a23425cb01c07e6dc0c3191317d.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/liantang-heung-yuen-wai-03-boundary-control-point/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3e48197f-3f57-4195-8981-aa70fb73f717</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:38:43 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RE – PROVIDENCE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>RE – PROVIDENCE</h1><p>The project aims to develop a dense urban fabric in the
center of Providence, Rhode Island and connect it with the
adjacent areas, which have been developed according to the
suburban sprawl model. The proposal focuses on three
different scales. The Urban scale, the Neighborhood scale
and finally the Street scale. On the Urban scale, three linear
infrastructure axes cross the center of Providence and
expand into the suburban areas. These axes organize a
sequence of free public spaces together with commercial
and recreational uses along them. They become poles of
attraction both to the local community and visitors from
other areas. The linear infrastructure provides the means for
transportation, both for pedestrians and vehicles. On the
Neighborhood plan, a small scale urban block typology is
applied in the plan, in order to infill the existing urban voids
and create new walk able neighborhoods. Three street
typologies are used in the plan. Great emphasis is given to
the pedestrian street network which connects the public
spaces. The street scale proposal includes the design of the
buildings’ facades and the guidelines for their overall
dimensions and number of built floors, in order to create a
unified experience of urban space. The master plan
reconstructs the city center and aims to reform the
surrounding suburbia in the future. It accommodates 15.000
more inhabitants in the city center than the existing plan.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/re-providence/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a7715fd6-b308-4db8-97c9-d4b13b18e58f</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:09:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DROSSCAPE & THE CITY THE CASE OF ELEONAS - ATHENS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>DROSSCAPE & THE CITY THE CASE OF ELEONAS - ATHENS</h1><p>This project addresses design strategies for the future
development of drosscapes in urban regions and their
relation with the city at large, having as an example the
district of Eleonas in Athens, Greece. It provides answers to
the problems of the district and understands the drosscape
as a potential for the urban revitalization of the city of
Athens. The design proposal is primarily concerned with the
urban transformation of the drosscape, and not its ecological
reclamation. To do so, the proposal focuses in multiple scales
of analysis and proposals. Eleonas is a huge area covering
approximately 2.350 acres. It is located within walking
distance from the historical center of Athens, while at the
same time it is the biggest undeveloped piece of land in the
city. The district today is characterized by its problematic
mobility infrastructure, the severe environmental pollution
problems, the accumulation of incompatible land uses and
its unresolved relation with the downtown of Athens. The
proposal aims to recognize and strengthen the urban
identities that have emerged in the area since it was an
agricultural land. It is an alternative solution to the ongoing
urban sprawl to the east part of Athens by bringing more
inhabitants in Eleonas and designing mixed uses, urban
communities. It solves the problems related to the
environmental pollution of the area and creates a wellarticulated
mobility network which would promote public
transportation. Finally, it reserves the existing road
infrastructure and the buildings.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/df5094aaa485c7b3f29d84b4cf1a99b77c14e209.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/drosscape-and-the-city-the-case-of-eleonas-athens/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4b4ade36-72e9-4006-a5d9-70abdd00f591</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 18:17:59 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mixed use]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Mixed use</h1><p>Masterplan for housing and commercial spaces development
in the region of Tavros, Athens, Greece. The plot is located on
a busy traffic node and the proposal re-organizes the
pedestrian and vehicular movements in the area.
Commercial and recreational uses are placed on the ground
floor and housing units are placed above them. Particular
emphasis is given in the configuration of residences, aiming
at variety and the changing relation of communal and
private spaces each time. The proposal organizes a second
level of public space for the local residents. It is located six
meters above the street level in order to protect them from
the adjacent noisy highway. Configuration of an interior
open space, running along the residential units, aiming at
their side to side arrangement; the sufficient ventilation and
natural lighting of all the apartments, as well as the creation
of an introvert network of daily meeting and communication
for residents. The designed open spaces are organized on
three scales - the small private spaces which belong to each
apartment, the medium sized communal spaces which act
as a cohesive tool for multiple apartments, and the main
open squares. The design aimed for a unique space
experience. In this way, the residents do not live in one of the
anonymous, repeating units of a block. They possess a
unique space, recognizable and distinctive from the others.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/aa9ee1ba6226a4d048e5db50ca9a859d25ce4820.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/5b15a48e-66cd-4457-a44d-33652f7c7892/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5b15a48e-66cd-4457-a44d-33652f7c7892</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:02:53 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elementary school]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Elementary school</h1><p>This project addresses the design of an elementary school in
Athens, Greece. The building includes twelve classrooms, a
library, a restaurant, office spaces and a hall for multiple uses.
On the ground floor movements are organized with a route
that begins on the east side of the plot, and continues,
covering every classroom, giving shape to the atrium in the
middle, and finally arriving to the tower, which is used as a
canteen. The main objective is the formation of an atrium
which would directly relate to every classroom and function
as a gathering space for the children during collective
activities. Great emphasis is given to the design of the
multifunctional interspaces of the building, in order to
produce meeting places for the students and a variety of
spaces from the closed, to the semi-open, and finally to the
open spaces. The school uses the adjacent empty plots of the
urban web for recreational activities. In the same way, the
open spaces of the school become multifunctional spaces for
the local community during the evening. Two main open
spaces are designed,. These are the encircled atrium and the
big open space that has direct relation with the restaurant,
the library and the inclined terrace of the underground hall of
multiple uses. The design of the underground hall of multiple
uses smoothly defines the boundaries between the school
and the urban web on the ground level.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/6cf1bf5b1f6f221c3447fdac42d70e5daa788c9c.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/342eb5ef-5d8f-4151-8bce-077aeb683f1a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">342eb5ef-5d8f-4151-8bce-077aeb683f1a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:00:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TV Tower]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>TV Tower</h1><p>Reconstruction of the unfinished TV tower and its' adjacent
territory in Yekaterinburg, Russia. The proposal aims to
redesign the abandoned TV tower of 220m height, to a new
building complex with recreational uses. The new
construction reaches 500m and becomes a powerful
landmark for the city. It becomes one of the tallest structures
in Russia and attracts many visitors and further investments.
On the ground level, visitors can enjoy an indoor tropical
landscape, use the hot water baths and the pools that work
all year round. Ice skating rinks are positioned outdoors.
Other uses include a congress center, an exhibition hall and a
hotel. The inflatable structure is superimposed on the existing
tower and an elevator can lift 300 people up to 500m high,
where they can enjoy the panoramic city view. Hot water and
hot air are the elements that form this landmark at an
affordable cost. The original tower was expected to reach
360m height. The proposal aims to improve to 500m. The city
of Yekaterinburg will become one of the 12 places in the world
which have had the power to erect structures over 500m
height, thus making its presence in the world grow
exponentially. The strategy is to create an inflatable
structure, a vertical aerostatic balloon that uses the existing
structure as its launching platform. Hot air and hot water
become the elements that give origin to the coolest city in
this part of the world.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/df06d86d38d1fef0e2a24d1a809ac13e76e06392.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/5df6f4bd-6c5c-4dac-bf33-317b232f67b9/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5df6f4bd-6c5c-4dac-bf33-317b232f67b9</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 16:59:12 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transformable surface]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Transformable surface</h1><p>Design of an interactive transformable surface which is able
to bend out of plane and scale at the same time. The surface
can be applied as a building facade skin or an interior space
partition and can interact to various stimuli, such as
temperature, air and light. The interactive surface can be
used in order to augment the acoustic experience of a space,
or control lighting, by changing it’s geometry and
permeability. In order to control the interaction of the skin
with external stimuli, sensors are placed on the surface and
mechanical parts force it to transform accordingly. The
prototype fabrication process focused on the design of the
ball and socket joints which connect the parts together and
allow for certain degrees of freedom. Finally, great
importance was given to the overall structural stability of the
surface and the way it can be attached to a building facade.
We applied molding and casting techniques using liquid
plastics in order to create the joints of the prototype. The
materials of the petals is pvc together with plywood.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/14713bd121d2d65097cc0b56820b2e47c2b7c1d8.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/2beabcb0-68ac-4fa2-838b-827d01ea21ae/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2beabcb0-68ac-4fa2-838b-827d01ea21ae</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 02:36:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Urban box]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Urban box</h1><p>Design of an aluminum kiosk, able to fit in different types of
public spaces in the city of Athens and accommodate
different uses according to different scenarios. It can operate
as a product selling point or an information kiosk. It can
adapt to most types of urban open spaces and withstand all
climate conditions. The folding sheath can acquire multiple
forms and accommodate different uses. It can be used for
suspending posters, products or even vegetation.
Advertisements can be placed on the top of the kiosk.
Multiple intermediary spaces are formulated through the
transformative nature of the Box, thus becoming an
transformative element of the urban space. Here, function
shapes form. In-out possesses a profusely protean nature,
reinforcing the social consistency of Mediterranean societies.
Indefinite and socially vibrant spaces are generated. A
multiform, fragile, plural and ephemeral space. The double
exterior surface of the construction generates satisfactory
variable spaces between the sleeve and the inside core. The
distorted yet rational form of the kiosk allows access from all
sides. The metal perforated surface can sustain interventions
when placed in an urban environment, without dissolving the
construction's overall aesthetic quality. The physical scale
prototype was exhibited at the Benaki Museum, Athens. The
design competition was organized by the Hellenic Institute of
Architecture and the sponsor of the construction was the
Aluminum Association of Greece.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/b0f508cd72d5b16817ca1afa206f7bb0f3b40754.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/de7f84a9-c5aa-45ee-81e1-710ce949ffb6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">de7f84a9-c5aa-45ee-81e1-710ce949ffb6</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 17:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>