<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[architecture & urbanism portfolio]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[architecture & urbanism portfolio]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:43:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TV - Tower]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>TV - Tower</h1><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/df06d86d38d1fef0e2a24d1a809ac13e76e06392.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/5df6f4bd-6c5c-4dac-bf33-317b232f67b9/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5df6f4bd-6c5c-4dac-bf33-317b232f67b9</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:24:04 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Boundary control point]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Boundary control point</h1><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/e2de9786a04e8a23425cb01c07e6dc0c3191317d.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/liantang-heung-yuen-wai-03-boundary-control-point/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3e48197f-3f57-4195-8981-aa70fb73f717</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[City Home]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/4dbc7f4b964a5d4d2cf7afab6ee24a2fa3f84f54.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/75a8994a-b706-47e4-901d-f4f96c989db9/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">75a8994a-b706-47e4-901d-f4f96c989db9</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:19:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Transformable surface]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Transformable surface</h1><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/14713bd121d2d65097cc0b56820b2e47c2b7c1d8.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/2beabcb0-68ac-4fa2-838b-827d01ea21ae/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2beabcb0-68ac-4fa2-838b-827d01ea21ae</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:25:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Re-Providence]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Re-Providence</h1><p>The project aims to develop a dense urban fabric in the center of Providence, Rhode Island and connect it with the adjacent areas, which have been developed according to the suburban sprawl model. The proposal focuses on three different scales. The Urban scale, the Neighborhood scale and finally the Street scale. On the Urban scale, three linear infrastructure axes cross the center of Providence and expand into the suburban areas. These axes organize a sequence of free public spaces together with commercial and recreational uses along them. They become poles of attraction both to the local community and visitors from other areas. The linear infrastructure provides the means for transportation, both for pedestrians and vehicles. On the Neighborhood plan, a small scale urban block typology is applied in the plan, in order to infill the existing urban voids and create new walk able neighborhoods. Three street typologies are used in the plan. Great emphasis is given to the pedestrian street network which connects the public spaces. The street scale proposal includes the design of the buildings’ facades and the guidelines for their overall dimensions and number of built floors, in order to create a unified experience of urban space. The master plan reconstructs the city center and aims to reform the surrounding suburbia in the future. It accommodates 15.000 more inhabitants in the city center than the existing plan.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/re-providence/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a7715fd6-b308-4db8-97c9-d4b13b18e58f</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 23:43:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Porto Pool Promenade]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/6e9273dca5d31ad8bf7b114fe707ca93ce371ccf.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/59a99e3d-8d65-43cb-bf91-19b1ee787e7c/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">59a99e3d-8d65-43cb-bf91-19b1ee787e7c</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:11:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MIXED USE]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>MIXED USE</h1><p>Masterplan for housing and commercial spaces development in the region of Tavros, Athens, Greece. The plot is located on a busy traffic node and the proposal re-organizes the pedestrian and vehicular movements in the area. Commercial and recreational uses are placed on the ground floor and housing units are placed above them. Particular emphasis is given in the configuration of residences, aiming at variety and the changing relation of communal and private spaces each time. The proposal organizes a second level of public space for the local residents. It is located six meters above the street level in order to protect them from the adjacent noisy highway. Configuration of an interior open space, running along the residential units, aiming at their side to side arrangement; the sufficient ventilation and natural lighting of all the apartments, as well as the creation of an introvert network of daily meeting and communication for residents. The designed open spaces are organized on three scales - the small private spaces which belong to each apartment, the medium sized communal spaces which act as a cohesive tool for multiple apartments, and the main open squares. The design aimed for a unique space experience. In this way, the residents do not live in one of the anonymous, repeating units of a block. They possess a unique space, recognizable and distinctive from the others.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/aa9ee1ba6226a4d048e5db50ca9a859d25ce4820.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/5b15a48e-66cd-4457-a44d-33652f7c7892/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5b15a48e-66cd-4457-a44d-33652f7c7892</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:11:52 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ELEMENTARY SCHOOL]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>ELEMENTARY SCHOOL</h1><p>This project addresses the design of an elementary school in Athens, Greece. The building includes twelve classrooms, a library, a restaurant, office spaces and a hall for multiple uses. On the ground floor movements are organized with a route that begins on the east side of the plot, and continues, covering every classroom, giving shape to the atrium in the middle, and finally arriving to the tower, which is used as a canteen. The main objective is the formation of an atrium which would directly relate to every classroom and function as a gathering space for the children during collective activities. Great emphasis is given to the design of the multifunctional interspaces of the building, in order to produce meeting places for the students and a variety of spaces from the closed, to the semi-open, and finally to the open spaces. The school uses the adjacent empty plots of the urban web for recreational activities. In the same way, the open spaces of the school become multifunctional spaces for the local community during the evening. Two main open spaces are designed,. These are the encircled atrium and the big open space that has direct relation with the restaurant, the library and the inclined terrace of the underground hall of multiple uses. The design of the underground hall of multiple uses smoothly defines the boundaries between the school and the urban web on the ground level.</p><img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/6cf1bf5b1f6f221c3447fdac42d70e5daa788c9c.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/342eb5ef-5d8f-4151-8bce-077aeb683f1a/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">342eb5ef-5d8f-4151-8bce-077aeb683f1a</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:11:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MIXED USE DEVELOPMENT OFFICE & CULTURAL SPACES]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cbea0160-9d8e-49d3-8e54-a32c23c3ffbd.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/mixed-use-development-office-and-cultural-spaces/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">85f56471-2f79-486e-a6bb-198175505776</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 20:14:11 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DROSSCAPE & THE CITY THE CASE OF ELEONAS - ATHENS]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/a7837d3d-29b2-43e5-8499-b29171d8c6bc.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/gsamartzo/drosscape-and-the-city-the-case-of-eleonas-athens/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">4b4ade36-72e9-4006-a5d9-70abdd00f591</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:03:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>